<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-08T03:52:51-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nia Applications</title><subtitle>Personal and Coding blog of an aspiring software developer. I code Android Applications and websites.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Quarantine Playlist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/10/Quarantine-Playlist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quarantine Playlist" /><published>2020-06-10T00:00:01-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-10T00:00:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/10/Quarantine-Playlist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/10/Quarantine-Playlist.html">&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Music Post. What songs have been getting you through civil unrest and quarantine? &quot; /&gt;

&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: Don't forget to change updates-personal or updates-coding--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/10/Quarantine-Playlist.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello readers!
Today’s post is about how I have been coping with all the craziness of the pandemic, racism, police brutality and overall bad news. In addition to talking with your loved ones and those who you seek out for support, music can also be a form of relief. I listen to music both to come to terms with reality and to feel better. That’s how this playlist is set up. I listen to a lot of genres, so this playlist is a mix. It moves through 12 songs from a place of feeling lonely, lost and angry to emotions in between and ending off in a place of hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLvZucUeG2u9BLKbApChEQR9auxyTKfh_j&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Here is the link to the Youtube Playlist &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VHhND-BkWdk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Alone &lt;/a&gt;by Gorillaz featuring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rootsmanuva.co.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Roots Manuva&lt;/a&gt;. During this time it can easily feel like you’re all alone. Please, text or call your family and friends, you are never really alone, but people cannot read your mind. No one will know you need support if you don’t ask for it. This song is rumored to be about Manuva’s outlook on the world. The pacing of the beginning builds a feeling of sadness and disappointment. A plea to again be alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=votgfrZpq7Q&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9ASHfb6woB3RvE6Mn-uK36z&amp;amp;index=73&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Breathe You In&lt;/a&gt; by Grace The Enemy. This band’s lead is a woman with a delicious scream and a lovely singing voice. The lyrics call out as if you are searching for validation, for redemption:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Holding on to this dream we’ve made&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m less if not crumbling,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know my mind won’t be the same&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As long as we remain undying&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breathe you in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwhelmed, As I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breathe you in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take my hand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show me life as I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breathe you in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breathe you in!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a call to perseverance, to keep going, to breathe in the good, and to remain undying in your stride. To fight for something higher, something better. I believe that I have needed this advice. When this social distancing began I didn’t want to take the situation in. I didn’t want to believe I’d be stuck inside for 3+ months. Once I took the situation in it became easier to see the pandemic not as a loss of everything I once knew, but a gain of something new and unexplored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SBjQ9tuuTJQ&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9ASHfb6woB3RvE6Mn-uK36z&amp;amp;index=69&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Pretender&lt;/a&gt; by Foo Fighters. I personally love this song and play it all year round. It gets me hyped up to do anything. The better part of my adult life has felt like a fight. I fight to survive, fight to drag myself out of poverty, fight to keep food on the table and a roof over my own head. Discovering this song a few years ago was very uplifting for me. Whenever I need the push to get back on my feet, I remember the lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What if I say I’m not like the others?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if I say I’m not just another one of your plays?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’re the pretender&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if I say that I’ll never surrender?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea that I’m somehow special, “not like the others” makes me feel empowered. The idea that I’ll never surrender, I’ll always keep going makes me feel strength. Not falling into the “pretender’s” play; that notion is very powerful. To be able to stand in the face of opposition and refusing to bow down. There has been a lot of discourse online about what they meant by pretender. For me personally the pretender is my depression. She wants to lie around all day pretending I can waste away. I pretend when I am depressed that my life isn’t worth living, but it always has been and will continue to be. This song gives me the strength to fight another day, to see my worth, and to keep growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Segueing into something lighter, next is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xS6sDhqVROs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Something’s Gotta Give&lt;/a&gt; by All Time Low. Despite the band’s name the music they make can be very relatable and even uplifting. I have felt fed up with the state America is in long before these protests. This song shines a light on feeling like you’re at your wit’s end. The chorus goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Wake me up, say enough is enough,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m dying to live, something’s gotta give.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pull me out of this sinking town,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m dying to live, something’s gotta give!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lyric is a plea, and I feel like I have been trying to “wake people up” to the truth. When I see those who are misguided it almost feels like they are asking me to enlighten them. They probably aren’t, but I can’t seem to stop myself from correcting misinformation. I want to wake people up to the truth of the racist system we are governed by. Wake them to the truth of white supremacy that hovers around every corner. Show them the truth that we all live on stolen indigenous land. Too many turn a blind eye to people struggling, but I will no longer blink in the face of ignorance. We are dying to live to our full potential. Black people are &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; being killed by both law enforcement and the bias within the system. Something does have to give, something has to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also relate to this song in the fact that we are all stuck inside from the pandemic, slowly passing the time, wanting something to give with the virus. I truly hope that we are at a new norm by the end of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment you realize generational pain has been being placed on the shoulders of every new generation because not enough changes are being made, you can begin to feel…hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hlgc3_4WL0M&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Kiri&lt;/a&gt; by Monoral. The Japanese rock band’s song was popularized by the grungy anime &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ergo_Proxy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ergo Proxy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You complete my fate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world unwinds inside of me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You complete my fate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The halo crawls away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You repeat my fate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rewinding all we can&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You refill my place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You refill my place, place”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lyrics speak to me a lot right now. The notion that history repeats itself, and that we are all completing each other’s fate, refilling each other’s place. The pattern of getting older and seeing someone younger in your place. It reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aishaoxley/status/1266965056027340800&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;this video &lt;/a&gt;that has been circulating online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course I can’t forget the chorus, the pleading echoing line sung 5 times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Come and save me.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple prayer of finding reprieve, redemption, for all the suffering to birth something worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we transition from that hopelessness to somewhere still sad but more level with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is another throwback &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XleOkGsYgO8&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9D5EwEgVTFEpfpgK4FOaaTo&amp;amp;index=7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Move Along&lt;/a&gt; by All American Rejects. “Move Along” is some of the best advice I have received. Sometimes it’s easy to succumb to our emotions, or the way we feel about situations in our lives. If you shorten transition time (idea I read from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12138871-18-minutes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Peter Bergman&lt;/a&gt;) and choose to look forward and keep going it will be easier to get through your day to day. As the song says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Speak to me!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When all you got to keep is strong&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move along, move along like I know you do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And even when your hope is gone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move along, move along just to make it through&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move along&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move along”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all you have is movement, moving into the next moment. I try to make it better than the last, the small steps add up to a significant recognizable change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1_O_T6Aq85E&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9ASHfb6woB3RvE6Mn-uK36z&amp;amp;index=44&amp;amp;t=0s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Snap Out Of It&lt;/a&gt; by The Arctic Monkeys. Too often I find myself stuck in a rut. Now that all this extra time is available to us it can be so easy to fall victim to spending a significant amount of time on our phones, or on social media. Many times a week I will find I am glued to facebook or twitter. I feel the pressing need to stay in the know. To be aware of the state of this country given all the protests and police brutality people are rallying against. Sometimes you need to snap out of it for your own mental health. Remember to draw the line for your own well being, because if you don’t you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; burn yourself out and we need everyone at their best right now. The best you possibly can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have gotten past the anger, we have gotten past the shock of the current moment, we have snapped out of it. Now we want to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sw-GdthJGuo&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9BLKbApChEQR9auxyTKfh_j&amp;amp;index=7&amp;amp;t=0s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Rise Again&lt;/a&gt;. This song is by Equilibrium, one of the most uplifting metal folk bands I’ve ever stumbled upon. This song came from my “Hype” playlist. Once you are past all your low-vibrational emotions, you need something to help you pick yourself back up. As the lyrics go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Let’s get forward, no time to rest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It doesn’t really matter if east or west&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So many roads are unexplored&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The journey is its own reward&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I feel it inside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My eyes are open wide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My heart will acclaim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The sun will rise again”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song is all about living to see another day and cherishing the moment. Garnering the courage to seize that moment and truly appreciating it. No matter where in your journey it happens to be you can appreciate it for what it is. It’s about finding the drive to pick yourself up as you move and act with intention. During this time inside it has been hard to stay productive at times. It’s okay if you stray, but coming back and rising again is crucial to making progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next in line is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rUmV-MorIKc&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9D5EwEgVTFEpfpgK4FOaaTo&amp;amp;index=30&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Patience&lt;/a&gt; by Tame Impala. The hypnotizing chorus, (and I say hypnotizing because that’s how all their songs make me feel) :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Just growin’ up in stages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Lay down, low down)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Livin’ life in phases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another season changes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And still my days are shapeless”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When quarantine began, the weather was still chilly. I still had to wear the lighter of my two winter coats. We have seen the change of the end of winter, to spring and now we have the summer solstice coming up on June 21st. I still had structure from school, but once the semester ended I have been feeling my days are a bit shapeless. To be fair to myself, this website was only 50% done when quarantine began, and now I am writing to you daily on this blog. Patience is also a virtue I have been struggling with, but am trying to have more with myself and others. I have been doing a ton of self discovery during this time, which is why the first and third lyrics resonate with me deeply. I’m taking things one day at a time, but cannot deny the transition I’ve been going through. The same can be said about the political unrest we are seeing in the air. All the anger and trauma are being transmuted into malleable changes. Police Departments across the country are having resources rerouted back into communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The embodiment of this next song, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uoS9rEfHKwo&amp;amp;list=RDEMlDgR2N2D5vOyaWLoYcMwdw&amp;amp;index=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Everybody’s Something&lt;/a&gt; by Chance the Rapper feat. Saba and BJ The Chicago Kid, is that no one’s life is nothing. Everybody is someone to somebody. Chance is an outspoken man of faith and he does right by it in this song. The bridge and chorus goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nice to see you Father New Year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Middle finger Uncle Samuel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shooting death with weighted dice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And hitting stains on birthday candles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know somebody, somebody loves my ass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cause they help me beat my demons ass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everybody’s somebody’s everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know you right&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nobody’s nothing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s right&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two lines are said to be Chance acknowledging the beauty of seeing another year, but flipping off Uncle Sam is a criticism of our government. Chance has not been all talk, he has put an enormous amount of his resources back into Chicago’s community and government. The next two lines are debated about whether he means death is weighting the dice in its favor for Chicago’s youth. Or if the youth are weighting them escaping death another year. In addition echoing back to what I was saying with The Pretender and depression, this is looking at it from the other side. “Cause they help me beat my demon’s ass”. No one should have to fight their demons alone. You matter to someone; at the very least one person in your life, even if that person happens to be yourself, or someone you haven’t even met yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearing the end, we come to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HSivlaSVk1k&amp;amp;list=PLvZucUeG2u9D5EwEgVTFEpfpgK4FOaaTo&amp;amp;index=17&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;We Got The Power&lt;/a&gt; by Gorillaz. I was trying to not repeat artists on this playlist, but this song is exactly what this playlist needs. At the end of the day through all the terrible things happening in the world, we have power. The chorus goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We got the power to be loving each other, no matter what happens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ve got the power to do that&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On a le pouvoir de s’aimer, okay?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We got the power to be ringing the great bell out there above us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We got the power for that&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We got the power to do that”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as humans can choose to feel unity. The lyric in French sung by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jehnny_Beth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Jehnny Beth&lt;/a&gt; translates to “We have the power to love one another, okay?” I urge you reader, when it is safe to go out once again, get to know your community. Your neighbors, the local shop owners, the people in your immediate area. You are even more fortunate if your town has a community center, check out local events. We see these racists online and ask how they can be so hateful and ignorant. It is because they aren’t exposed to people who don’t look like them. They make assumptions and don’t fact check their news. They follow an orange menace who spews hate, bigotry, xenophobia and much more. Spending time with people in your community is a great way to make friends and feel empathy for others. We have always had the power to keep loving each other. Be the example you want to see in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kzQWCeguH30&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Crystal Clear&lt;/a&gt; by Hayley Williams. This song is fairly new, it is about seeing things as they truly are and as Williams says in the echoing chorus, much like a mantra:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Crystal Clear, I won’t give into the fear.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these troubling times it is important to look at the situation without fear, but rather objectivity. Giving into fear will only make your decisions erratic and possibly dangerous. Seeing things in new light can be incredibly liberating. The second I started looking at quarantine as a detriment I lost all power in the situation. I now see this just is, and I need to make the best of it and have been attempting to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading, let me know what songs you are using to cope with in the comments below!
Lastly I found this artist while searching for songs, while I don’t know any of them well enough to put them on this playlist, Yves Tumor, an upcoming Black Non-Binary artist deserves your time, so please lend your ear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/N0c7lVHMyaY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Kerosene!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LJ4o9ppV4yg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Romanticist/Dream Palette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next time and stay safe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img id=&quot;img-id&quot; src=&quot;/../../images/yt.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; oncontextmenu=&quot;alert('Please don\'t download this photo!');return false;&quot; /&gt;
  &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Justice for Breonna Taylor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Justice for Breonna Taylor" /><published>2020-06-05T00:01:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-05T00:01:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor.html">&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Today is my birthday. It is also Breonna Taylor's. Instead of talking about me I would like to talk about her story.&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello my readers, hoping you are keeping hope amid these unpredictable times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is my birthday. It is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/breonna-taylor-fbi-investigation-shooting-louisville-police/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Breonna &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Breonna_Taylor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Taylor’s&lt;/a&gt; birthday. Instead of talking about me I would like to talk about her story. Breonna would have turned 27 today. She was an essential worker, an EMT. She was a University of Kentucky graduate and steadily pursuing her career in the medical field. She was serving her community and her country by working during a  pandemic. That in itself is admirable,  the bravery it takes to work during the spread of a deadly virus should  not be overlooked. In an &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/06/04/869930040/as-the-nation-chants-her-name-breonna-taylors-family-grieves-a-life-robbed&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt; interview released yesterday family and friends talked about her and her life. How she said she would make a name for herself. I want that to sink in. She was very young and had her whole life ahead of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her life was taken, family described the loss as feeling they were robbed. The incident occurred past midnight on March 13th, 2020. We know now that three cops in plain clothes entered her home on a no-knock warrant. Kenneth Walker, Breonna’s boyfriend said that after hearing loud bangs on the door, Breonna repeatedly asked &lt;em&gt;“Who is it?”&lt;/em&gt; with no response. Walker, a licensed gun owner then armed himself due to lack of response. Police used a battery ram to enter the apartment. Walker shoots first, logically assuming these men are burglars as they did not identify themselves. He then shot one robber in the leg. Officers responded by opening fire of &lt;em&gt;more than 20 rounds&lt;/em&gt;, shooting Breonna at least &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;8 times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, ending her life. Kenneth was arrested at the time, but has since had all &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boston25news.com/news/trending/charges-dropped-against-breonna-taylors-boyfriend-police-chief-retires-fbi-joins-probe/MDUWBEGADNHSVKIWVV3G42BZLA/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;charges dropped&lt;/a&gt; on grounds of self-defense. Breonna had an ex-boyfriend who was in custody for selling drugs, and suspected of shipping them to Breonna’s home. She had nothing to do with the drugs but the no knock warrant that a judge awarded was &lt;em&gt;based on this suspicion&lt;/em&gt;. No drugs were found in the apartment. This negligence cost Breonna her life. Family and friends tell the truth, that she was not that type of person, who would risk the life she had for something as silly as drugs. It has been 84 days since her death. On May 21st the F.B.I. began an investigation but the three cops are still out there employed on the force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No-knock_warrant#cite_note-nyt19m-1 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; and use of no-knock warrants is all bad news. The number of no-knock raids has increased from 3,000 in 1981 to over 50,000 in 2005. From 2010 to 2016 31 civilians died at the hands of officers using a no-knock warrant and 81 civilians died during SWAT raids using no-knock warrants. More than half of civilians killed were a minority, 42% of them African American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is heartbreaking to hear how a woman full of so much life and promise is no longer with us. Police brutality has been on the rise in the US. From 2013-2019, police in Kentucky killed &lt;a href=&quot;https://mappingpoliceviolence.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;122 people&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; Black people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://mappingpoliceviolence.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;three times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; more likely to be killed by police than White people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read my last &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; you may recall that Black people are also three times as more likely to die from the COVID-19. Breonna was risking the last of her days in more ways than one. If you are born Black it should not warrant suspicion, the color of your skin should not be a death sentence. This injustice has not gone unnoticed. Protests are happening to garner support and awareness for Ms. Taylor. We need to continue putting pressure on the Louisville Metro Police Department to arrest Myles Cosgrove, Brett Hankison and Jonathan Mattingly. Recently we saw how the same fight for accountability can have positive results as the degree of murder in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/3-more-minneapolis-officers-charged-george-floyd-death-derek-chauvin-n1222796&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;George Floyd&lt;/a&gt; case was raised as well as the arrest of other complicit officers. We need the same swift action for Breonna Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    
   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are resources to either help Ms. Taylor’s family or to put pressure on the LMPD to hold officers accountable for taking Breonna’s life. If you have any additional resources either contact me through my contact page or email them. I will add them to the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This List was last updated: 6/18/2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://justiceforbreonna.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Website called Justice for Breonna, resources on how to take action.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/K6DVLZWJ9B?amp=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Email link&lt;/a&gt; that is prewritten to Assistant Chief of police of Louisville KY as well as Mayor of Louisville. All need is to insert your name, city and state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/Script-for-KAG.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Email script and link I put together.&lt;/a&gt; Copy and paste the script, filling in your name/city/state to demand justice for Breonna Taylor from Kentucky’s Attorney General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/andy-beshear-justice-for-breonna-taylor?utm_content=cl_sharecopy_22077589_en-US%3Av4&amp;amp;recruiter=852527036&amp;amp;recruited_by_id=20111c80-ad63-11e8-9a3a-a76981400f4b&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_abi&amp;amp;utm_term=psf_combo_share_initial&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Justice for Breonna Taylor Petition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CHlSMOSA/status/1268253644920483840/photo/1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Call this number and demand accountability.&lt;/a&gt; You can find a prewritten script &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BerniceKing/status/1269636063632527360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/9v4q2-justice-for-breonna-taylor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Official GofundMe for Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;. Proceeds go directly to her family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/r3w76-raising-money-for-breonna-taylor-and-david-macatee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;A second GoFundMe for both Breonna and David McAtee&lt;/a&gt;. You can read more about McAtee &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/02/us/david-mcatee-louisville-what-we-know-trnd/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://actionnetwork.org/fundraising/louisville-community-bail-fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Louisville Bail Fund for protesters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BerniceKing/status/1269636063632527360/photo/2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Call/Email demanding Justice for Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/10/Quarantine-Playlist.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img id=&quot;bre&quot; src=&quot;/../../images/breonna2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breonna Taylor&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Black Lives Matter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Black Lives Matter" /><published>2020-05-31T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-31T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html">&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Black Lives Matter. The system that oppresses Black people in this country cannot be reformed. All lives cannot matter until Black Lives are treated as they truly matter.&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Readers. I hope that all of you are safe where you are and that your families are well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you all have been keeping up with the news. We have yet again failed Black people in this country [USA]. The death of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/27/us/george-floyd-trnd/index.html&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Article about the life of Floyd&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/29/us/derek-chauvin-george-floyd-worked-together.html&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Article about the Murder of Floyd&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floyd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 6 days ago is another heartbreaking tragedy. He was accused of using a fake bill at a store on completely unfounded grounds. The incident ended with him begging for his life, because three cops were on top of him, one, Derek Chauvin, kneeling on his neck for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;8 full minutes and 46 seconds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. He was murdered because of the color of his skin. Gruesomely two months before we saw this same story of Black lives being robbed happen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/kentucky-governor-calls-for-investigation-of-breonna-taylor-killing_n_5ebc625fc5b6cdefa7e8fb38&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Article about Taylor's tragic death&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breonna Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; who had &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, literally &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to do with the case the officers were actually investigating. Merciless, her life was taken in the comfort of her own home. We only got a drop of decency from the department who released her partner Kenneth Walker, who was defending himself and Breonna from the officers invading their home. The month before we shed tears over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2020/05/ahmaud-arbery-shooting-georgia-explainer.html&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahmaud Arbery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; who was killed for simply jogging in his own neighborhood while Black. The hate crime went unpunished for nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/2020/05/08/it-took-georgia-officials-2-months-to-arrest-and-charge-father-and-son-with-ahmaud-arberys-murder/&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;2 full months&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, his killers living their lives as if they hadn’t ended someone’s life prematurely just because they could. The white supremacy complex so many people in this country subscribe to must come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a teenager my dad had a close friend who lost his father. His father was a Black Vietnam War Veteran. He fell asleep on his life alert, an honest mistake. When he woke up, he called to let them know what had happened. Dispatch sent word, telling these cops that their services were no longer necessary at the scene. These white cops did not listen. They took matters into their own hands. After exchanging harsh words with our Veteran, who rightfully refused to let them into his home, they called him the n-word with hard r, entered the apartment, and tased and shot him, ultimately ending his life. I say his name, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Kenneth_Chamberlain_Sr&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Wiki Page on Chamberlain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenneth&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleausa.org/report-blasts-review-of-wppd-calls-justification-of-chamberlain-shooting-chilling/&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Article about the incident&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chamberlain&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdny/prus-attorney-s-office-closes-investigation-death-kenneth-chamberlain&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;Closing Chamberlain's Investigation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sr.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; just as I say the three I mentioned earlier because this senseless killing must stop. Officers must be held accountable. The Police lied on reports, saying Chamberlain was armed, and failed to include the exchange where they called him the n-word. We later got &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/westchester-man-killed-cops-not-knife-lawyers-article-1.2850274&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DNA Proof&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Chamberlain was unarmed and after many battles in court got audio released to us, which is how we know the incident was racially charged. In 2012 a Grand Jury decided no criminal charges would be made against these officers. Police brutatlity is law-sanctioned murder. They claim they fear for their lives when in reality they are megalomaniacs who instigate and provoke to justify unecessary use of violence. Mr. Chamberlain’s life was taken from us because of  ignorance, negligence of value for human life, racism and white supremacy. Kenneth Chamberlain Sr. deserves justice. Anthony Carelli and Steven Hart are still free walking around, and most likely still on the force. Carelli was involved in another federal case &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/sources-identify-white-plains-anthony-carelli-triggerman-fatal-shooting-retired-marine-article-1.1056394&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot;&gt;3 years earlier&lt;/a&gt; for brutally beating two twin brothers while working on a disordlerly-conduct arrest. Too often these officers who kill people  have a track record. When I still lived in my hometown I went to protests for Mr. Chamberlian, I attended his candle vigil each year held in front of the White Plains Department of Safety, and I went to court battles to show support. I speak up about these issues because I cannot bear to see any more Black lives taken in vain. On top of it all, we are still in the midst of a global pandemic in which Black people are dying at &lt;a href=&quot; https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/may/20/black-americans-death-rate-covid-19-coronavirus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;three times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the rate of White people. It is no coincidence that this statistic has come about. It is a direct result of institutionalized racism. We have a problem in this country and it needs to be addressed and fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plight for justice has always been something I have cared about. I am biracial, and I know we have a bad rap sometimes because some of us don’t know how to act yet (I’m looking at you &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lucky_Shanghai/status/1217664668434604032?s=20)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Beware, this is some clown shit.&quot;&gt;Jeanie Reuter&lt;/a&gt;). I am Black and Chinese. The thing is, I have privilege as a light-skinned person. I am doing my community a disservice if I don’t use it to uplift Black voices— which are too often brushed off, ignored, or crushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not care if you are tired of hearing it: BLACK LIVES MATTER.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All lives cannot matter until Black Lives are treated as they truly matter. It is time for change. I am of the belief that this starts with defunding law enforcement. The system that oppresses Black people in this country cannot be reformed. It was not created with them in mind, in fact some argue &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/issues/juvenile-justice/school-prison-pipeline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;it was created to keep them oppressed&lt;/a&gt;. We need to start over where everyone is truly equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading, until next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the end of this post. Below are some resources, threads of petitions, bailout funds, gofundme’s for the names above, threads of protest tips, links to therapist offering services for those who need to talk these traumatic emotions out, and resources for white allies to educate themselves as well. I will continue to add and update this post. Also, if you are feeling particularly generous, the last gofundme is for my Aunt Donna, a disabled Black woman who does not have a permanent home right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list was last updated: 6/18/2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mayarichardsun/status/1265676677549559809&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt; Therapy Thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TatiannaTarot/status/1267511432394035200&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread for Energy work, healing&lt;/a&gt;. I believe priority is being taken for Black Youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.self.com/story/black-mental-health-resources&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Mental Health Resources for Black People&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nxbrxth/status/1266239760248393735&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Safety Tips for Protesters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdenae.com/blm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;General Resource and Education site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blacklivesmatter.space/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Resource masterpost&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Black Lives Matter Org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joincampaignzero.org/#vision&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Campaign Zero’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kiwiscigarettes/status/1265767579739512833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of Petitions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatters.carrd.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Website called “Ways To Help”.&lt;/a&gt; Petitions and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; https://signatures.carrd.co/ &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Petiton masterpost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://saytheirnames.carrd.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;How To Help Website&lt;/a&gt;. Petitions/Places to Donate/ Text/Call Actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/us-senate-hands-up-act?recruiter=186170836&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_abi&amp;amp;utm_term=psf_combo_share_initial&amp;amp;recruited_by_id=535372c0-733b-11e4-abc5-176b86b32b70&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hands Up Act&lt;/a&gt; Petition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sign.moveon.org/petitions/nonewyouthjails&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Petiton for No new Youth Jail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/williamson-county-pd-justice-for-javier-ambler?recruiter=771678484&amp;amp;recruited_by_id=3da05e60-8ebe-11e7-a7e6-55007d82a2ca&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Petition for Javier Ambler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_courttnneeyy/status/1271125322080022528&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of petitions that are short on signatures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/allow-california-s-prisoner-firefighters-to-work-professionally-after-release?signed=true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Petiton: Allow California’s Prisoner Firefighters to Work Professionally After Release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/meItedhearts/status/1270212402827669507&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Another thread of petitions to sign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pendingpetition.carrd.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pending Petitions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vSrT26HMWX-_hlLfiyy9s95erjkOZVJdroXYkU-miaHRk58duAnJIUWKxImRkTITsYhwaFkghS8sfIF/pub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Document of multiple resources.&lt;/a&gt; Petitions, places to donate, call and email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AM1R4HSCAVE/status/1267202201132265472&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of Various Resources.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/niawillie/status/1266771198777724932&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread I made of bailout funds&lt;/a&gt; for protesters. Some content is NYC specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bailfunds.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;An additional list of bail funds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sorrybythway/status/1267469168300998656&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of Places to Donate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/b/520/bundle-for-racial-justice-and-equality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Bundle for Racial Equality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humblebundle.com/fight-for-racial-justice-bundle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Racial Justice Bundle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iconickbeauty/status/1271584309221167104&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Crowfunding thread for Black Trans people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/poesrogue/status/1269303523490971649&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Organizations to donate to that help Black Trans People&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bothamjeanfoundation.org/donate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Donate to the Botham Jean Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Xa9Av-NfuFsWBHlsMvPiqJHdNedZgnCRW56qAS-7PGQ/mobilebasic?urp=gmail_link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Resources for Accountability and Action for Black Lives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/u/0/d/1BRlF2_zhNe86SGgHa6-VlBO-QgirITwCTugSfKie5Fs/mobilebasic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Anti Racism Resources for White people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=1118672045179268&amp;amp;set=pb.100011094495325.-2207520000..&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Graphic about Covert White Supremacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1hpub-jkm9cLzJWqZSsETqbE6tZ13Q0UbQz--vQ2avEc/edit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;More Anti-Racism Resources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dj_diabeatic/status/1266563804437110787&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Informative Anti-Racism Graphic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://padlet.com/nicolethelibrarian/nbasekqoazt336co&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Anti-Racism Resources for all ages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thebolditalic.com/where-do-i-donate-why-is-the-uprising-violent-should-i-go-protest-5cefeac37ef9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Common FAQ’s answered for White People about Black Lives Matter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.welcometostratagem.com/post/10-habits-of-someone-who-doesn-t-know-they-re-anti-black&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Article about recognizing Anti-Black habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/a-fund-for-blackled-mental-health-supports?utm_source=customer&amp;amp;utm_medium=copy_link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=m_pd+share-sheet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;A Fund for Black-led Mental Health Supports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/starstrickenSF/status/1267307734744985601&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of where to donate, petitions to sign and Anti-Racism resources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sorrybythway/status/1267469168300998656&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of more places to donate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/homeless-black-trans-women-fund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Fund for Homeless Black Trans Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/louisville-mayor-greg-fischer-justice-for-david-mcatee?recruiter=862253145&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_abi&amp;amp;recruited_by_id=ca6cbd70-2414-11e8-ab29-25fa8a73a71b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Petition for David McAtee a protester who was murdered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://officialblackwallstreet.com/directory/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Offical Black Wall Street&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/lists/1198727909525131264&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Black owned Business you can support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buyfromablackwoman.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Buy From A Black Woman&lt;/a&gt;. Nonprofit Org that raises awareness to Black Women owned Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webuyblack.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Largest Market place for Black owned Business&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/milkyapron/status/1267881192306561025&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of Black Owned Clothing/Fashion stores&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stephano.me/fashion/blog/black-owned-goth-brands-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;List of Black Owned Punk/Goth Brands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://themadmommy.com/black-owned-etsy-shops/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Black Owned Etsy Shops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/couturedymond/posts/10207861202685044&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Black Owned Restaurants in NYC&lt;/a&gt; split up by bourough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NitaTyndall/status/1269702757352701952&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of books by Trans people for children sold at Black owned bookstores&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AriLennox/status/1271173707185127425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thread of Black owned Businesses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stylishcurves.com/black-owned-plus-size-clothing-brands/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;List of Black owned plus size brands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shoppeblack.us/2020/05/black-owned-tea-brands-you-can-purchase-online/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;List of Black owned Tea brands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/u/0/d/12iRz-DAMLiwGrMmWlhMZRKZKQJf6lP1IE1-uJuXwvYc/mobilebasic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Website to help support Black Content Creators&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Zk06JtFXxIHs05jRCRQ5nmUVYdVi2BgF2S6tMGdqJv0/edit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Eye Witness accounts of Police Brutality&lt;/a&gt;. Open Google Document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BerniceKing/status/1269636063632527360/photo/2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Call/Email demanding Justice for Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-donna-find-a-home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;My Aunt Donna’s 
GoFundMe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
     &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/06/05/Justice-for-Breonna-Taylor.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img id=&quot;vigil&quot; src=&quot;/../../images/vigil.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Me at a Candle Lighting Vigil for Kenneth Chamberlain Sr. in 2014.&quot; oncontextmenu=&quot;alert('Please don\'t download this photo of me!');return false;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Check-In</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Check-In" /><published>2020-04-14T04:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello reader, 
I have been social distancing for almost a full month now. I usually stay at my partner’s on weekends and last month after a shift at my part time job they convinced me to stay in. That same night DeBlasio closed restaurants so I was temporarily (I hope?) laid off. My classes have been an adjustment, but I have been doing my best given the circumstances. Part of this week was “Spring Break” so I did get some reprieve from the anxiety and stress it all brings. 
I have finished working on the subscribe function to my website, I want everything to be perfect before I start to promote everything. In the email a peice of code that is hidden on this page, shows up in the email, linking to my blog post. (Hint it’s right under the date, only visible if you mouse over it!) I haven’t gotten the chance to work on comments again, nor the chance to work on making each page responsive to browser window size/ branching to mobile. One step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, I have been working on my anger, both for my sake and my partner’s. Being stuck inside isn’t an excuse to take my anger out on anyone, but if you read my Self Discovery Journal Prompts 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Journal Prompt post&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; you may recall this is something I have been working on. I think I actually have a 
good handle this time. I just need practice. I feel better about everything this time around. I am equipped with some mental mantras for when I’m in the moment and already had all the post-anger tools like meditation down pact.
I am going to try to learn Chinese (Mandarin, not my family’s tongue Toisanese). I redownloaded an app I used before, but ultimately ended up stopping because I didn’t have time. I have no shortage now. I wish that I could paint, but since I am not home I have no supplies. I have been attempting to motivate myself to work out, but it is not going well. I am reading two books right now. Ryan Holiday’s &lt;em&gt;The Obstacle is the Way&lt;/em&gt; and Steven Forrest’s &lt;em&gt;The Inner Sky&lt;/em&gt;. I think it’s good, one self-help and one for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you doing to keep busy during this social distancing time? Are you keeping hope? I sincerely hope this all passes soon and we all come out safe and ready to reclaim our lives soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending love. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-div&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/05/31/Black-Lives-Matter.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website Update and COVID-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website Update and COVID-19" /><published>2020-03-27T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello readers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is your favorite coder coming to you from home in this scary social distancing period. As I am sure you all know, we as a community are facing the pandemic of COVID-19. This post will be my offering to you, to stay logical in these trying times, but first, a coding update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are here, you are on my site, which is nearly finished! Every page on here I have spent tireless hours 
tinkering away. If there are any issues please reach out to me! I have just set up my website’s newsletter, which will provide you an update when I post here on my blog, so please scroll down and subscribe with the form in my footer! Next I will be working on comments for blog posts. Communication is key for any aspiring business. I also just generally enjoy talking with people, and with being stuck inside for the health of everyone, the internet is such a gift, why not use it? On my site most of the pages are in HTML/CSS, but for the blog I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I have to pick up a few things to work in .markdown files, but it is going pretty well. Jekyll was suggested for github pages, where I host, because the pages are static. This means that my content is built exactly as is, everytime there is a request. It communicates directly with the server. As opposed to dynamic webpages that can generate different HTML for each request, most of it being built on the fly. Using jekyll I don’t need a CMS or anything. It is sort of perfect for what I want to achieve. For the sake of preserving my website (because in the future I may redesign it) below are some screenshots. I am very proud of myself for the work I have done. I do want to shout out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/@oleg-magni&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Oleg Magni&lt;/a&gt;, who took the photo of the sky that I use for my background on this site. I actually copied the photo in paint and flipped it horizontally after rotating 180 degrees and appended it to the original, so when my background repeats (when my webpage extends past the viewport) the image isn’t choppy, but rather flows like an endless sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;

![alt-text](/images/w1.gif &quot;Home Page&quot;) 
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/w1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Blog post&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/w2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blog&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/w3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Portfolio Page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/w4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blog post&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-talk-about-covid-19&quot;&gt;Let’s talk about COVID-19&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a deep breath in, filling your belly. Hold it for a few seconds. Then let it all out, and let your body go lax. It is important to keep our composure in a time like this. To use logic and not let our emotions control us. This strain of the corona virus will pass, as long as we try our best to flatten the curve. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/mar/25/chinas-premier-warns-local-officials-not-to-cover-up-new-covid-19-cases-as-hubei-reopens&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;China allegedly&lt;/a&gt; has no more domestic cases and people in Hubei, just on the outskirts of Wuhan are permitted to travel once more. Wuhan is following suit, according to the article on April 8th. We have the most cases in my state NY right now. Essential employees still go to work daily, risking their lives for us all. I am hoping a vaccine will be developed soon. All of my college courses have been moved online now, and I was laid off from my part time job. That is actually why I have had so much time to work on this site. I know that we all want to go outside and feel the sunshine on our faces, but it is important to stay away from each other and stop the spread. Do not hoard things at the grocery store. Picking up one extra bag of beans won’t hurt, but emptying shelves is selfish and unecessary. Do right by your community and think rationally about what you are buying and it’s quantity. Please wash your hands and avoid touching your face. No one is expendable. I deeply wish that I were in a position to help those experiencing homeless-ness right now. I cannot imagine how hard this will be affecting them. Are there enough shelters and warm beds? Enough food to go around? If you buy a meal with whatever change you get from people on the subway and people stop riding the subway, how will you buy your daily meal? My heart hurts for those people. I hope they make it out okay. Remember that 80% of cases are mild if you are not immunocompromised. Hold your composure and stay inside to protect your loved ones. I hope to bring you better news next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2020/04/14/Daily-Check-In.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here Hello readers!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self Discovery Journal Prompts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self Discovery Journal Prompts" /><published>2019-06-30T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently watched a favorite youtuber of mine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkDpZatLuIc&amp;amp;t=3s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;lavendaire&lt;/a&gt; and she had a video about journaling + self discovery. Here is the reader-friendly version of it. I started these at the beginning of the month, instead of all in one day. This did come from my journal/diary, I have changed names to protect the people in my life’s privacy. This was before developer week, and before/near the growing pains post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you feel at the moment?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel lost. I feel like I know what I want and I know what I need and those things are not in the middle of a venn diagram. They are separate right now. I need income. I want to freelance full time. I want to be well off, I don’t want to struggle. But maybe I need to. I feel upset. I did a forgiveness meditation today and I just felt so fake. The meditation said, “forgive yourself, you did your best.” but I feel like it’s just not true. I think I could have done better. I could have force myself up and out on my bad days, but I didn’t because I felt shitty. Would I have passed if I went to my classes and didn’t fall behind? Yes. 90% certainty. Depression fucking sucks. Poverty sucks. I deserve better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do I need more of in my life?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money. Money is the main thing holding me back. I tell myself it comes easy and frequent but lately it has been hard. I want to go on lavish dates, I want to dance (badly but idc) at clubs, I want to do fun things that cost money with my partner, I want to go out and do fun things with friends. I want a spa day where I do everything I haven’t been able to. I want to act like money isn’t an issue. Self love. I fucking hate myself yo. It’s so hard to like me. I feel like an unfinished piece of art. I feel like I know who I want to be but I am not them. And it fucking sucks. When I was 17 I thought I would have at the least my own studio by now. At least one App on the app store with 100 dl’s. I was supposed to be hot shit in my own fucking way, but instead I’m this nobody who keeps failing classes. And I’m just stuck with me. This shell of “want” but without any of the gusto, confidence or can-do. Motivation. Motive to work, motive find a part time job, motive to workout, motive to put myself out there. Time. Time for my needs, time for my wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What would make me happy right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like the above sort of went into it. Oodles of money, time, to be farther along in life. To like myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is going right in my life?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My love life. Every other area could use work. My partner makes me feel worthy of love. I feel so messy and yet he still wakes up and cherishes my company for some reason. Yeah, I’m nice, yeah I’m tough, yes I’m kind, but none of that counts for anything if I’m always struggling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What am I grateful for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My relationship / his existence in my life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My good clients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My brain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My laptop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-My room&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I haven’t had any recently, but Bud (Legalize it!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-SNAP and fair fares&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-This journal, like the ability to be able to vent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Good people. People who get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When did I experience joy this week?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week my friend S and I drove out to Robert Moses Park. We are going to go there for my birthday which is coming up. Sometimes and I skeptical of S(in his energy he can be really negative sometimes and I worry I won’t be able to be around him). We haven’t hung out alone in a while. But I had a great time actually. I burned out towards the end, but that was understandable. The beach+good company always brings me joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List my small victories and successes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-This week I painted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-This week I played Minish Cap, a zelda game I’d never played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-One of my clients finally responded to me, and I started to work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I had a really good interview, even if the job was not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I was real with myself in a letter I wrote to dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s bothering me? Why?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me. I thought I’d be farther by now. It’s frustrating because it’s just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are my priorities at the moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this moment I am focused on Applying to part time jobs, upwork jobs and scholarships. Anything else is really secondary. Maybe trying to type once a week and start flossing daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I love about myself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question reminded me to do my affirmations, I will make a mental note to be better with them, at least once a day. It’s so hard for my to make eye contact with myself and just say those 3 affirmations without crying. I know they are true, so I’m not sure why I am crying. I guess because I feel like I haven’t had the opportunity to be kind lately, or be creative. Intelligence is necessary for work, but weirdly it was the last one I said, and the one that had me break down. I think I know they are true but don’t believe them. I don’t know how that’s really possible. I can only hope saying them each day will make me believe them. To answer this question, I will go with: that I am someone worthy of my partner’s love. Because right now I don’t feel so great about a lot of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who means the world to me and why?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner obviously. Because he is generous and kind hearted. My head is in a bad space. I won’t say more than that to keep it positive. That one quality of his has won me over time and time again though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If I could share one message with the world, what would it be?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the fuck off of your high horse. We are all flesh and blood. We are all human. We all deserve a safe place to rest our head and food to eat and clothes on our backs. We all deserve respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What advice would I give to my younger self? [Do I take that advice now?]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot about this one. Would I go back and time and tell myself to starve? No. I would go back in time and tell myself that instead of taking out target, and paypal credit cards to apply to SNAP then. If I had been on SNAP sooner I wouldn’t have racked up so much debt, and could have saved. I would have been banging last summer enough to come off of it with better savings. So, my advice would be to ask for help more, whether it be the government, my friends, family or my partner. I do take this advice now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If I had all the time in the world, what would I do first?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I would choose leisure first. I feel so, restricted right now. I want to paint, I want to draw, I want a massage, I want a spa day. I want to relax until I get bored and then want to work. I want to write. I want to dance. So much repressed desire because business comes before pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is draining my energy, how do I reduce or cut it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like cutting my bad client off was the correct call. He was draining a lot of energy and creating unnecessary anger. I don’t think anything is really draining me except like existential dread of needing to work to survive. But that’s just life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does my ideal morning look like?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this question, I can try to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up refreshed at 8:30am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I meditate for 10 minutes, or mind splat/morning pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make breakfast and eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brush my teeth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What lesson did I learn this week?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not confuse setbacks for settling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the 29th secret of Paul Angone’s “101 Secrets for your twenties.” Needing part time work isn’t settling. It does not mean I am a failure because freelance work isn’t as stable. It’s just what the situation happens to be. I’m sure when I have more experience it will all seem silly I was upset. So I’m continuing to interview and apply for Administrative jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does my ideal day look like?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up refreshed at 8:30am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I meditate for 10 minutes, or mind splat/morning pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make breakfast and eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brush my teeth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin to code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take a lunch break, maybe a bus ride to the water or a walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come back and code or apply to jobs and scholarships until 5pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cook and eat dinner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch some anime or play a videogame&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I clean my space&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I meditate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes me come alive, when was the last time I truly felt alive?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerts. Swimming in the ocean. So at the beach last week. But moshing and screaming lyrics I love really gets my heart pumping, both literally and figuratively with love. Nothing else really gets me like the pit. Exhilarating energy and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What/Who inspires me the most? Why am I drawn to those inspirations?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billie Joe Armstrong, Marsha P. Johnson. Hayao Miyazaki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billie is Tough. He is my Bi icon. His era of music just makes me feel understood, my anger at the American government, my in my feelings. His voice and Green day in general make existing easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marsha, also a LGBT icon, inspires me with bravery, courage. I am wearing a pride shirt right now, because it is Pride Month, and her efforts to simply be accepted as a trans black woman paved the way for many young queer people today, especially here in NYC. She is dear to my heart. She is a martyr because shortly after the first pride her body was found in the Hudson River. She died fighting for our rights. A noble person she was. I aspire to be as dedicated as her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hayao Miyazaki reminds me that life is whimsical. Life is amazing. It is adventurous and worth being vulnerable for amazing endeavors to bloom. All of his movies give me that everything is going to turn out fine feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where does my pain originate? What would need to happen for me to heal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my pain comes from me. Specifically Emotions, Depression, anxiety and self worth issues, which stem from dad. Dad is out of the picture so what needs to happen is that I continue to learn to enjoy my own company, being nicer to myself, and learning to in general be patient. Healing takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well that’s all for this post. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2020/03/27/website-update.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Developer Week 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developer Week 2019" /><published>2019-06-23T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-23T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hello-readers&quot;&gt;Hello Readers!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week I attended an event called “Developer Week NY”. I got an invite from a group I am in on meetup.com, that covered most of the cost [lucky break (:], it was a lot of fun. I went mostly to immerse myself around like minded people, expose myself to the up and coming tech and to learn. I met a lot of interesting people, and I may have even found some potential mentors! Most importantly it has helped me get my resume out there for jobs in my field. I have a phone interview on Tuesday! My search for part time work and more freelance work also continues. I had a great time going to the talks and gaining valuable knowledge and opportunities. I’m feeling an overwhelming sense of gratitude for, well everything right now. I may not be exactly where I want to be, but I feel like I am at the least heading into the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos from the conference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/dw.gif&quot; alt=&quot;My bdage&quot; /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
 &lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/dw2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Misty Robotics display&quot; /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/dw3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Main Stage&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently just finished a book that has me feeling better, it was : 101 secrets for your twenties by Paul Angone. It was a little religiously leaning, but besides that I enjoyed it. I recently celebrated my birthday (June 5th if anyone is my birthday twin?) so I am now 22. The summer is here (Solstice was yesterday) and I am taking things one day at a time. I will find the right job. I will pay rent. I will thrive. I will do work I love. I will live to the fullest. I will laugh, I will dance, I will rejoice because life will turn out alright. I am reaching out to friends (now that I can sort of afford to hang a little more) and it makes me feel better to not be so isolated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, some short work updates. On my current work project I am flustered. I am familiar with Google’s Firebase database, but not MongoDB. Today I got the mongo shell to make a connection to my cluster and it’s databases but not the database and collection connected to my stitch app. I did get my android app and stitch app to successfully connect but inserting a new document isn’t working (I think, I was hoping to see the data using mongo shell, but no luck so far) If anyone out there has advice please comment, I need it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been painting, here are the start of two I’ve done so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swamp and Tree painting base&quot; /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;img id=&quot;lighthouse&quot; src=&quot;/../../images/lighthouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse Painting&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my birthday, I received new brushes and paints, so I started the lighthouse painting, but will come back to the tree one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still working on my website. I am considering migrating to blogger or wix. I did not know you couldn’t use your own code with only the free tier here. I know it’s weird to ask, but if you have an opinion on either, good (or bad) drop a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, thanks for reading this update. When I get that notification it warms my heart that my words are sometimes read/heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-div&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/30/self-discovery-journal-prompts.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Growing Pains</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Growing Pains" /><published>2019-04-12T14:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T14:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;catchup&quot;&gt;Catchup:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on my website (If you have advice on how to code custom WP pages hit me up!! I have questions about Ads), I had some trouble with some clients and upwork but I am over that hump now. I couldn’t secure an internship this summer and as a result and am looking for part time work. I finished the semester with flying colors… in 3/5 classes. Hoping for a better next semester. Still alive. I wish to find a mentor, but am shy and also don’t always like people, which is a problem, I feel like either my standards are too high or the people I’m meeting just aren’t that great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anyways&quot;&gt;Anyways,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing is what I want to talk about today.  Lately I have been working on myself a lot. I am not where I thought I would be when I moved out three years ago. I write that now, and it seems so short, yet I know so much has happened. I thought that I’d be living without roommates by now. I thought I would be well into my career by now, but I am only at the beginning and it’s frustrating. To feel like I am brimming with energy, creativity, ideas and potential, only to bust my ass on jobs that limit me so I don’t become homeless. I have too many great ideas that sit in a drawer simply because other things are taking priority right now. I am not fulfilled. One thing this feeling has taught me is that I need to learn some patience. Things don’t always operate on your projected schedule. I want to so badly graduate college, I do not regret my gap years, but it’s hard to be left behind. But I’m back in school and I’m trying my best. I hope that counts for something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working on my rage. I moved out when I was 19 to get away from my abusive father. I resent him, for a million and one reasons, but being angry all the time, does nothing to further my life. After we lost his mother’s house (my childhood home) just months after I moved out, he went MIA. Off the face of the earth. Probably changed his number because he won’t pick up when his mother calls. He didn’t help his sister pack, or try to help her, It was just me. He just dipped. I want to say that karma will get him. I want to say that he will understand how his abuse has affected us all, and will regret his actions, but I can’t. I know that I just want to be nothing like him. I know that I cannot waste another one of my precious seconds or brainpower on thoughts of him. Besides this post, after writing a therapeutic letter and finding a good rage song (my friends is actually in a band and this song is the best [saw them live, I would die for them omg]) listen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1_IN8NgYYkA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, I am moving past that issue. I just know that I want to end the bad cycles he put me through. I want my future kids to enjoy their childhoods, to feel like I care about them, that they are worthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I have been working on [thanks to a push from my partner] is to be more proactive. This for me usually means asking for help before I actually am in dire need of it, financially. In general I have been better with asking for help. It’s just hard getting over the initial “I need help part”. I like to do things on my own. That way I’m the only one to either praise or blame. If people help me and I fail I’m letting them down. If it’s just me, it’s just me. I pride myself in my independence but sometimes help is important. I’m still a little unconvinced if you can’t tell, but I can’t deny the fact that my friends, family, and partner have helped me and I appreciate their time and efforts. Needing help doesn’t make me inadequate as a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, being kinder to myself, self love. I saved this for last because it is the hardest for me to talk about. I have hated myself for so long, until now. I can’t even recall when it began. I know it starts with my father’s unnecessary commentary, but when did I begin to internalize it, when did it become my norm? I honestly have no idea. I am mad at myself because I feel like I should be further in life. Because I feel I am not good enough in more ways than one, it has limited me. But hating me won’t make me better. If I constantly focus on what is wrong I am not growing. I am not moving forward. Being nice to myself is so hard. Every negative self loathing thought feels like a battle. Dismissing these thoughts (luckily) gets easier as I go along. Even looking myself in the mirror is hard, but doing it each day and saying an affirmation, makes it… doable. Metal really helps. Feeling all that rage and knowing you’re not alone? [seriously tho checkout that link above] I am sure of myself. I have been for years, but I want to be able to be proud of myself. To think I am deserving of love, to think I am deserving of good friendship, to give myself some credit. To wake up and know that I have worth, simply because I am here, that I am worthy, that I am doing my best, and that that is enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am ready to love me. I am ready to let useless rage go. I am ready to both ask and accept help. I am ready for abundance. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-div&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/06/23/developer-week-2019.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello! Hello! From your sleepless coder!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello! Hello! From your sleepless coder!" /><published>2019-04-12T00:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m working on revamping my website, as I may be doing more HTML work this summer and want to have something to show for it. Below is a gif of my Nav Bar with a hover effect I just finished. The extra space on the left will be for my new logo, which I’m in the process of designing. I know it’s incredibly simple, but it’s 12 am and I’m damn proud. More to come, definitely. What goes on a home page, I am beginning to ask myself. Know any good example sites? Comment them! Have any feedback? Get at me! I’m lonely at this hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/website.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gif of my site&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/09/lets-play-catch-up.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-personal/2019/04/12/growing-pains.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here So I’m working on revamping my website, as I may be doing more HTML work this summer and want to have something to show for it. Below is a gif of my Nav Bar with a hover effect I just finished. The extra space on the left will be for my new logo, which I’m in the process of designing. I know it’s incredibly simple, but it’s 12 am and I’m damn proud. More to come, definitely. What goes on a home page, I am beginning to ask myself. Know any good example sites? Comment them! Have any feedback? Get at me! I’m lonely at this hour.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Play Catch Up!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/09/lets-play-catch-up.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Play Catch Up!" /><published>2019-04-09T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-09T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/09/lets-play-catch-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/09/lets-play-catch-up.html">&lt;!-- Need to copy/paste to each post: --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;feed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/09/lets-play-catch-up.html&quot; title=&quot;Link to this post&quot;&gt;For my email subscribers, please click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;since-i-last-wrote&quot;&gt;Since I last wrote…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My internship ended and I did start and my first freelance job. I have been doing freelance work since. It’s tumultuous and trying right now. I have a “100% job success rate”(a system by upwork) which I have worked incredibly hard for but have been having a hard time. For one, my main project/source of income is capped at 10hrs a week. I cannot live on just that so I am constantly having to seek secondary income to survive. I have had my fair share of weeks of starving, and am sick of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changing-pace&quot;&gt;Changing pace,&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School is taking a huge toll on me. I am doing terribly in one class, borderline on another and exceptionally well in the last 3. I am still mending my sleep schedule and attempting to exercise more. Today I did 17/30 min workout before I couldn’t anymore and became extremely sluggish. I fell asleep at my desk (and somehow ended up in bed (I work from home and rent a room where I reside so everything is in one place)??). I missed both classes due to the small setback. I am trying to be better, even if it doesn’t look like it. Yesterday I had a very long heart to heart with my partner about my life. They are the wisest person, I swear. They always know what I need, and lucky for me they don’t sugar coat. I need the hard truth so I can move forward accordingly. They gifted me the affirmation: I deserve better. My life will be great. One step at a time. I have been trying to be nicer to myself. It’s hard. It’s so easy to beat myself up when I mess up because I am the only one to blame. I am so kind to others but cannot seem to impart the same kindness to me, until now. I’m sure it will become easier with time. I don’t love myself. It’s something I’ve got to work on. I am afraid of failing, being nothing more than a quitter and doomed to be unhappy the rest of my life, as my father would say. My partner thinks anytime I am in doubt or upset to ask myself what they would say. The exercise has helped me realize my internal hate monologue stems from my deadbeat dad. Changing how you think is arduous, but I am doing it for the immense peace and benefits after successfully shifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coding-wise&quot;&gt;Coding Wise:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;scale-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/../../images/blog-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;website screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am coding my own website from scratch. Brushing back up on HTML because my partner might try to get their company to hire me!! I want to do my very best because they are sticking their neck out for me, and I appreciate it. Still working on my client’s project, but I am bound by an NDA so my lips are sealed. I scrapped the PAPP (women targeted app I mentioned in the last post) but instead, this summer will try to work on my first idea for an app ever, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to anyone reading this. I enjoy comments, advice, but please be constructive and not an ass. Till next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;edit-march-26th-2020&quot;&gt;Edit: March 26th, 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is actually the first steps I took in bringing together the very website you are visiting today! How time flies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;button-post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2018/06/23/oppurtunity-update.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Previous Post&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://niaapps.github.io/niaapps-blog/updates-coding/2019/04/12/hello-from-your-sleepless-coder.html&quot; class=&quot;post-button&quot; id=&quot;button-nxt&quot;&gt;Next Post&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For my email subscribers, please click here</summary></entry></feed>